Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/michaelbervell (LinkedIn) www.MichaelBervell.com (Personal) www.testparty.ai/ (Company)

Top Skills

Public Speaking Leadership Community Outreach

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
French (Professional Working)
Akan (Elementary)

Certifications

HBX CORe (Credential of Readiness)

Honors-Awards

Jackie Robinson Scholar
National Coca-Cola Scholar
International Huggable Hero
Global Teen Leader
National Achievement Scholar

Publications

The Past and the Present of the Levine Music School

Data Ombudsman for the New International Data Bank: Surveillance Capitalism, Privacy, and Big Data

Michael Bervell

Founder & CEO at TestParty | Bringing Al Automation to Accessibility

New York, New York, United States

Summary

TestParty is an automated digital accessibility platform for WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) conformance. We help companies expand their market potential while avoiding lawsuits through increased compliance with Section 508, EAA, ADA Title II / III, AODA, EN 301 549, IS 5568, the Stanca Act, and more.

Michael Bervell is a Ghanaian-American angel-investor, entrepreneur, and author. He studied Philosophy at Harvard with a focus in computer science.

His debut book "Unlocking Unicorns" was an Amazon best-selling new release and finalist for the 2022 Independent Author Network book awards. It investigates the founders, philosophies, and strategies for building a unicorn company in Africa, Asia, and the Middle East.

In 2007, Bervell co-founded "Hugs for" an international, student-run non-profit organization focused on using grassroots strategies to develop countries around the world. To date, "Hugs for" has fundraised over \$500,000 of material and monetary donations; impacted over 300,000 youth around the world; and expanded operations to 6 countries (Tanzania, Ghana, United States, Uganda, Kenya, and Sierra Leone). Because of his work, Bervell was awarded the National Caring Award in 2015 (alongside Pope Francis, Dikembe Mutombo, and 7 others).

Bervell is the youngest elected director of the Harvard Alumni Association and was the youngest President of the Harvard Club of Seattle. He has helped to found and lead a variety of organizations including the Enchiridion Corporation, a marketing consulting company; Billion Dollar Startup Ideas, a media and innovation company; and the Sigma Squared Society, an internationally-recognized professional society for entrepreneurs under the age

of 26. He has experience working as a Venture Fellow at Harlem Capital, Portfolio manager at Microsoft's Venture Fund, Program Manager at Microsoft, and Software Engineer at Twitter.

His various efforts have earned him recognition as a Samvid Scholar (2022), Warnick Fellow (2021), Jonathan Hart Prize Winner (2019), GE-Lloyd Trotter Scholar (2018), World Internet Conference Wuzhen Scholar (2017), Walter C. Klein Scholar (2017), United Health Foundation Scholar (2016), Deutsche Bank Rise Into Success Scholar (2016), Blacks at Microsoft Scholar (2016), Three Dot Dash Global Teen Leader (2015), Jackie Robinson Foundation Scholar (2015), National Achievement Scholar (2015), Coca-cola Scholar (2015), Elks Scholar (2015), AXA Achievement Community Scholar (2015), Build-a-bear Workshop Huggable Hero (2014), and more.

Experience

TestParty

Founder and CEO

June 2023 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Bringing AI automation to digital accessibility. www.TestParty.ai

Backed by the US Government (NSF), Harlem Capital, the Urban Innovation

Fund, Soma Capital, and others.

ProFound

Founding Member

May 2024 - Present (11 months)

ProFound is a powerful professional network of disability-inclusive leaders. Together, we are elevating disability inclusion and accelerating accessibility across our organizations and the workforce.

Harvard Alumni Association
Elected Director
July 2022 - Present (2 years 9 months)
Cambridge, Massachusetts, United States

Elected by more than 32,000 alumni to represent the alumni body on the HAA Board of Directors. Directors serve as representatives on the Board and support the HAA's effort in developing volunteer leaders and increasing alumni engagement.

Hugs for Ghana Co-founder and Executive Director July 2007 - Present (17 years 9 months)

Hugs for Ghana is an entirely student-run, 501c(3) non-profit organization dedicated to hand-delivering material and monetary donations to underprivileged children in schools, hospitals, and orphanages. We have fundraised over \$500,000 worth of material and monetary donations.

Billion Dollar Startup Ideas

Founder & Author October 2019 - October 2024 (5 years 1 month)

Author of "Unlocking Unicorns" a #1 Amazon new release and 2022 IAN Book of the Year Awards Finalist! I blog about one new startup idea every day. 300k page views, 500k viewers on TikTok, and 750k unique readers from 175+ countries & 2,000+ subscribers to my daily newsletter. BillionDollarStartupIdeas.com.

United Nations

Senior Accessibility Consultant - SDSN Youth May 2023 - August 2023 (4 months)

Spearheading the digital accessibility transition to help SDSN Youth thrive. Sustainable Development Solutions Network Youth (SDSN Youth) is one of the world's biggest networks of young leaders working together to accelerate solutions towards the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).

Databook Chief Of Staff April 2022 - July 2022 (4 months) Palo Alto, California, United States

Working directly with our CEO to give every enterprise sales executive unfair access to the highest-quality company and industry strategic insights.

Harvard Club of Seattle 6 years 2 months

President
July 2020 - July 2022 (2 years 1 month)
Seattle, Washington, United States

For 129 years, the Harvard Club of Seattle (HarvardSeattle.org) and its alumni have served Harvard, Seattle, and Western Washington through philanthropic

service, educational activities, and community building. I am the 18th president since The Club's incorporation.

Vice President Of Programming June 2019 - July 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Crimson Achievement Program Chair August 2018 - July 2020 (2 years)

Greater Seattle Area

Led the inaugural Crimson Achievement Program.

Student Director

June 2016 - June 2019 (3 years 1 month)

Greater Seattle Area

- Created over 30 summers events between Seattle-area interns and alumni from Harvard
- Moderated a discussion between Seattle Sounders owner Adrian Hanauer and Portland Timbers owner Merritt Paulson, MBA '00
- Organized mentorship meetings between current students and alumni both on and off Harvard's campus

Sigma Squared Society

5 years 10 months

Global Executive, United States

January 2020 - June 2022 (2 years 6 months)

Sigma Squared Society is a non-profit organization and global community of the world's most ambitious young founders under 26 selected for their impactdriven initiatives and their ability to transform broken industries.

Executive (Kairos Society)

September 2016 - January 2020 (3 years 5 months)

The Kairos Society seeks to develop entrepreneurs from universities around the world. The organization supports programs at over 100 universities in 35 countries.

- Managed the interview and nomination process for new fellows annually (Fall and Spring)
- Maintained connections with the local fellows, investors, mentors, and advisors
- Hosted exclusive experiences for fellows to connect on campus and with other campuses regionally

Microsoft

3 years

Portfolio Development Manager November 2020 - April 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Worked at M12, Microsoft's Venture Fund.

Program Manager

August 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Redmond

- Working on the Internet of Things.
- Founder of Growth Groups, Microsoft's early-in-career network and training program with 1,500+ members and alumni in 26 countries.

Program Management Intern

July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

Greater Seattle Area

[SUMMER 2] May 2018 - August 2018

- Created "Lunch and Learn," Microsoft's 2nd largest intern program, to connect EVPs, CVPs, and Directors to interns
- Managed 20 interns and 2 full-times to organize 140 networking lunches over 12 weeks, engaging 1,300 interns
- Expanded capabilities by 2,000% for IoT Device Management Dashboard (from 100,000 devices to 2 million devices)
- Interviewed 15 IoT experts to craft a business-analysis of Microsoft's \$750M+ IoT business and identified gaps

Program Management Intern

May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months)

Greater Seattle Area

[SUMMER 1] May 2017 - August 2017

- Managed a team of 4 full-time engineers to develop an improved "Internet of Things Device Management Dashboard"
- Expanded capabilities by 2,000% for IoT Device Management Dashboard (from 100,000 devices to 2 million devices)
- Created and organized 11 "Lunch and Learn" programs between Microsoft executives, EVPs, CVPs, and 125 interns

M12 - Microsoft's Venture Fund
Portfolio Development Manager

November 2020 - April 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Greater Seattle Area

M12, Microsoft's venture fund, invests in enterprise software companies primarily in the Series A through C funding stages with a focus on applied AI, business applications, infrastructure, security, and vanguard technologies.

Harlem Capital

8 months

Venture Fellow

May 2020 - August 2020 (4 months)

Harlem Capital Partners is an early-stage venture capital firm on a mission to change the face of entrepreneurship by investing in 1,000 diverse founders over the next 20 years.

Winter VC Intern January 2020 - April 2020 (4 months) Greater New York City Area

Education

Harvard Business School

Master of Business Administration - MBA

University of Washington

Master's degree, Communication in Digital Media

Harvard University
Bachelor's Degree, Philosophy

Kamiak High School High School